Stanislaw M. Ulam Papers 1916-1984 Mss.Ms.Coll.54
American Philosophical Society
- Series VII. Talks and interviews, 1937-1984, 2.0 Linear feet 4 boxes
  Outlines, notes, diagrams, abstracts, announcements, autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, and final transcripts of Ulam's extensive talks and interviews given during his life. Most of the talks represented in this series date from the middle to the end of Ulam's career (1950s-1980s), with the bulk falling during the 1960s and 1970s, with outlines of talks, discussions, and seminars predominating. Giving these "talks," as Ulam referred to them, came to be one of the most time-consuming activities in the scientific community during the latter part of his career. The talks and interviews of this series are arranged alphabetically by the title provided by Ulam. In many cases, the materials are identified only with a city as title; consequently, a number of the talks are filed alphabetically by the city in which they were given. Unidentified talks are located in four folders labeled "miscellaneous notes/outlines."
  Transcripts of audio-taped interviews with Ulam and colleagues are also housed in Series VII. Transcripts are interfiled alphabetically by title with other materials in the series, except when the name of the interviewer (usually an author preparing an article) has been identified. Such transcripts are located under the interviewer's name. Among the most noteworthy "interviews" is a transcript of a conversation between Ulam and long-time friend and collaborator, Gian-Carlo Rota. This transcript, in two parts, documents fifteen anecdotal conversations covering a wide range of topics, including thoughts on mathematics, philosophy, and John von Neumann.
  - A.A.S. meeting, talk at Gainesville, FL., 9 Mar. 1974 (Box Series VII-1)
    Outline
  - Albuquerque, talk, 4 Oct. 1951 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Albuquerque, talk, 7 May 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Albuquerque, talk in, 1971 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Analogy in mathematics, 1980 (Box Series VII-1)
    Notes
  - Applications of the notion of distance between combinatorial structures and growing patterns (Box Series VII-1)
  - Arden House, talk, 8-10 Oct. [1952]; 3 folders (Box Series VII-1)
    Outlines
  - Aspen conference on education in applied mathematics, remarks, 1966 (Box Series VII-1)
    Transcript
  - Astronautics symposium, second annual. Denver, Colorado, 28-30 Apr. 1958 (Box Series VII-1)
    Schedule
  - Astronomical Society, talks in the, 11 July 1951; 2 folders (Box Series VII-1)
  - Astr[onomical] Society, talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-1)
  - Astronomical Society, Purdue, talk, 23 June 1967 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Berkeley, talks, 2 Nov. 1955 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Berkeley, talk, 23 July 1960 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Best number of science, 14 May (Box Series VII-1)
    Notes for talk
  - Binary branching process, 1967 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Binary processes, talk on. Siam, 13 June 1967 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Biology, seminar, 27 Feb. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Biology department, Boulder, talk, 22 Nov. 1968 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Biology seminar, talks, 1973 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Biophysics meeting, U. of IL, 1967 (Box Series VII-1)
    Transcript of discussion
  - Boca Raton, talk, 1978 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boca Raton, talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, talk, 9 July 1956 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, talk, 29 Oct. 1962 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, talk in, 20 May 1968 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, talk, 10 May 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, talk, 30 Sept. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, [talk in], 25 Dec. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder, talk, 30 Sept. 1983 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder[?] conference, talk at the, 3 Dec. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder (for SIAM), talk, 15 Nov. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, 16 Nov. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, Fall 1975 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, 7 Oct. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, 14 Oct. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, 26 Oct. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, talk, Dec. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, talk, 12 Oct. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, talk, 21 Oct. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Boulder seminar, talk, 28 Oct. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brain, the, 11 May 1981 (Box Series VII-1)
    Outline of talk in Paris
  - Brain, the. Talk at Los Alamos on, 1981; 2 folders (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brain talk, 1981 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brookhaven, talk, 7 Dec. 1956 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brookhaven, talk, 27 July 1965 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brookhaven, talk, 1978 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brooklyn, talk, 15 Apr. 1955 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Brown University, talk at, 26 Apr. 1957 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Bryn Mawr, talk, 1983 (Box Series VII-1)
  - California, lecture tour, 7-23 Jan. 1959 (Box Series VII-1)
    Outline,schedule
  - Cambridge, talk, 3 Apr. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Chicago, talk, 25 Apr. 1952 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Chicago, talk, 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Chicago, talk in [?] meeting, 17 Nov. 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Chicago colloquium, talk, 24 Feb. (Box Series VII-1)
  - Chico, talk, 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - [Collapse of stars], 1967 (Box Series VII-1)
  - College de France, talk in (Flato), n.d. (Box Series VII-1)
  - Colloquium in E. E., 22 May 1957 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Colorado, University of. talk, 1981 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Combinatorial problems in the theory of patterns and process, 1971 (Box Series VII-1)
    Transcription
  - Combinational seminar, talk in [Gainesville, FL?], 1982 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Combinatorics, talk on, 17 Apr. 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Combinatorics in biology [?]Flato lecture, 1977 (Box Series VII-1)
    typescript
  - Combinatorics in Pisa, n.d. (Box Series VII-1)
    Outline of talk
  - Combinatorics of the lattice of points with integer coefficients in Euclidean space, 12 Feb. 1976 (Box Series VII-1)
    Outline for seminar
  - Complexity of projective Algebras, 1977 (Box Series VII-1)
    On same page: Denver, talk in, 1977 (outline)
  - Computer colloquium, talk in the, 15 Nov. 1973 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Computer seminar, talk, 10 Nov. 1958 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Computers in number theory, 18-23 Aug. 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
    List of attendees
  - Computing seminar, talk, 23 Oct. 1956 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Continuum mechanics seminar, talk, 9 Apr. 1957 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Davis, talk, 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Davis seminar, 30 Jan. 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Davis seminar, 27 Feb. 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denton [TX], talk at, 1981 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 1978 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 12 Oct. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 18 Oct. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 15 Nov. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 26 Oct. 1967 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 19 Jan. 1968 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 18 Oct. 1968 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 23 Feb. 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 2 May 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk, 29 Nov. 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver, talk in. A.A.A.S., 30 Dec. 1961 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver High School, talk, 18 Jan. 1962 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver Medical School, talk, 10 Jan. 1968 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver [?] Medical School, talk, 1973 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Denver Seminar, talk, 10 Dec. 1969 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Detroit, lecture, 25 Feb. (Box Series VII-1)
  - Dijon, seminar, 22 May 1980 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Dijon, talk, 23 Mar. 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Distances, 15 Feb. 1977 (Box Series VII-1)
    Outline and transcript for seminar
  - Duluth, talk, 1979 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Dynamics of infinite systems of mass particles, 1958 (Box Series VII-1)
    Abstract; Internat'l Congress of Mathematicians, Edinburgh
  - Else, John, 1979 (Box Series VII-2)
    Transcript of interview for doc. on JRO
  - Engineers, talk to, 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Evans, Christopher., June 1976 (Box Series VII-2)
    Transcript of taped interview, "Pioneers of Computing"
  - Feigenbaum, Mitchell. "An interview with mathematicians Stan Ulam and Mark Kac", 1982 (Box Series VII-2)
    Transcript of interview in LASL Science
  - Florida, talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Florida, University of, talk, 1982 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Frontiers of Science, talk, 12 May 1976; 2 folders (Box Series VII-2)
  - Future of mathematics, talk on. Colorado Springs, CO, 14 Jan. 1964 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Future of mathematics, talk on Colorado Springs, CO, 12 Jan. 1969 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Future of nuclear energy in space, 1963; 2 folders (Box Series VII-2)
    Transcripts of panel disc.
  - Gainesville, FL, seminar, 17 Oct. 1979 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 23 Jan. 1974 (Box Series VII-2)
  - [Gainesville, FL] seminar, 30 Apr. 1974 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 7 May 1974 (Box Series VII-2)
  - [Gainesville, FL] seminar, [1974?] (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 16 Feb. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 2 Mar. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 23 Mar. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 26 Oct. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, 17 Nov. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, talk, 9 Jan. 1974 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar, talk, 5 Feb. 1974 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL seminar talk, 7 Dec. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL talk at [Mill?], 4 Dec. 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gainesville, FL, talk in seminar, 17 Oct. 1979 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Game theory session, Washington, 1975 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Games, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
    Outline for talk
  - Games, talk on, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gamow lecture, 1982 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Garrett-Shannon seminar, talk, 15 Dec. 1956 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gauss, lecture on (technical), n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - General conundrums abt. Nervous system etc., 2 May 1983 (Box Series VII-2)
    Outline of talk in NY
  - Goddard Space Center, talk, 11 Oct. 1968 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Gödel, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Göttingen, talk, 1972 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Graduate Club, talk to, 19 Dec. 1967 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Graduate student seminar, talk in Boulder, 15 Jan. 1962 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Group theory of S[?], n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Harvard colloquium, 28 Feb. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Harvard/MIT colloquium, talk, 21 Feb. 1957 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Harvard/MIT colloquium, talk, 18 Oct. 1956 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Harvey Mudd. General talk in Claremont, 28 Sept. 1977 (Box Series VII-2)
    See Series I: Baird, Bridget
  - Harvey Mudd College, talk, 1977 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Holland, talk, 1975 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Houston, second talk, 17 Mar. 1967 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Hydro[?] conference, remarks, 16 Oct. 1958 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Infinities, talk on, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Infinities in mathematics and physics, AAAS talk in Denver on, 23 Feb. 1977 (Box Series VII-2)
    Outlines and notes
  - Inst[itute] Poincare, conference, 28 Nov. 1950 (Box Series VII-2)
  - IBM, Poughkeepsie, discussion, 29 Dec. 1956 (Box Series VII-2)
  - IBM, talk, 12 July 1961 (Box Series VII-2)
  - [International conference of mathematics?], talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - International congress of mathematics, talk at. Edinburgh, 1958 (Box Series VII-2)
  - International school of nonlinear mathematics and physics, lectures, 1966 (Box Series VII-2)
    Transcripts 1 and 2
  - International school of nonlinear mathematics and physics, opening lecture, 1966 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Istanbul [Turkey], talk, 1970[?] (Box Series VII-2)
  - Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, talk before, 1958[?] (Box Series VII-2)
  - Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, talk before, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
    Project ORION transcript
  - Jurzykowski Found[ation], talk (Box Series VII-2)
    Draft
  - Jurzykowski Foundation, talk, [1975-76?] (Box Series VII-2)
  - Kempner colloquium on Scottish Book and new problems. Boulder, Colorado, 1982 (Box Series VII-2)
  - La Jolla, talk, 29 June 1960 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 13 Nov. 1956 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 8 July 1959 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 5 Sept. 1967 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 8 July 1968 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 1971-1972 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 22 July 1976 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 26 Aug. 1976 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, 1982 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk in, 1983 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos, talks, 1980 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos and mathematics, 1978 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos colloquium, 16 Mar. 1951 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos colloquium talk, 25 Apr. 1955 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos colloquium talk, 31 Mar. 1959 (Box Series VII-2)
    Outline with diagrams
  - Los Alamos commencement, talk, 6 June 1962 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos meeting talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos science, past and present, 1982 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos talk on problems, 1980[?] (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Alamos "Think Tank", speech, [1956-57?] (Box Series VII-2)
  - Los Angeles, talk, 18 July 1968 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Las Cruces, evening talk, 27 Apr. 1956 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Las Cruces, talk, 27 Apr. 1956 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Madison, talk, 13 May 1963 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Madison, Wisconsin, talk, 4 May 1956 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Maryland, talk, 29 Apr. 1961 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Math Club, talk in [?], 4 Feb. 1976 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Math and natural sciences], 1971 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Math meeting, talk at. Gainesville, FL, 9 March 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Math problems, seminar on, 2 Oct. 1951 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Math seminar, talk in. Boulder, 27 Oct. 1961 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Math seminar, talk in. Los Alamos, 26 Sept. 1960 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Math sociology (McPhee's) seminar, talk, 3 Dec. 1969 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Mathematical physics, talk, 12 Sept. 1969 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Mathematics club, second talk (Box Series VII-3)
  - Mathematics and computer, what lies ahead. Missoula, MT, 1973 (Box Series VII-3)
    Outline; partial audiotape, transcription
  - Mathematics in the future (the new hundred years?), talk in Boulder (Box Series VII-3)
  - Measure theory talk, 2 Apr. 1966 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Metropolis, discussion with Nick, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - MIT, talks, 1972-1978 (Box Series VII-3)
  - MIT/Cambridge, talk, 9 Jan. 1957 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Misc. notes/outlines (Box Series VII-3)
    - Folder #1, 1937-1981; n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
    - Folders #2-4, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Monte Carlo calculations problems of mathematical physics., Nov. 1958 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Talks in California (Box Series VII-3)
    - Folder #1 (Box Series VII-3)
    - Folder #2 (Box Series VII-3)
    - Folder #3 (Box Series VII-3)
      Notes and transcripts
  - Multiplicative processes continued, talk in the Mathematics Club, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Munich, talk, 18 July 1966 (Box Series VII-3)
  - N.C.A.R. Library Assoc, talk, 7 June 1976 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Newsweek, 18 July 1960 (Box Series VII-3)
    interview
  - New York, talk, 18 Apr. 1967 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Notre Dame symposium, talk, 15 Apr. 1962; 2 folders (Box Series VII-3)
  - Nova University, Fort Lauderdale. 2nd annual advisory board meeting, 1 Mar. 1967 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Oak Ridge, talk, 17 Feb. 1976 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Odd problems and remarks (Box Series VII-3)
  - [On Gamow, Condon, Gurney and quantum physics] (Box Series VII-3)
  - Oregon State, talk at. Corvallis, Oregon, 15 Jan. (Box Series VII-3)
  - ORION, talk on, 17 Mar. 1976 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Paris, talk in, 18 Aug. 1967 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Paris, talk in], 30 Mar. 1970 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Philosophy and computing, 13 Oct. 1982 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics, 1982 (Box Series VII-3)
    Outline and transcript
  - Physics, mathematical colloquium in Austin, 29 Nov. 1982 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics colloquia, 1971-1973 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics colloquium, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics for mathematicians, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics for mathematicians, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics for mathematicians seminar, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
    misc. notes and outlines
  - Physics for mathematicians seminar, talk, 18 Apr. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Physics for mathematicians] seminar, talk, 17 Sept. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Physics for mathematicians] seminar, talk, 24 Sept. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Physics for mathematicians] seminar, talk, 1 Oct. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Physics for mathematicians] seminar, talk, 8 Oct. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - [Physics for mathematicians] seminar in Cambridge, talk, 18 Oct. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Physics seminar, talk, 18 Oct. 1956 (Box Series VII-3)
    Outline; Harvard/MIT
  - πME, talk, n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Polish Institute, talk, 25 Nov. 1966 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Polish mathematics, [on], n.d. (Box Series VII-3)
  - Poughkeepsie, talk, 11 June 1950 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Princeton, talk, 1972 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Princeton seminar, 24 Feb. 1956 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Problem of geometry; the greatest group, seminar on, 20 Feb. 1975 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Problems to discuss with Ronald Graham, 1979 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Producto Mania seminar, 18 Jan. 1977 (Box Series VII-3)
  - "Property preserving" transformations, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Series VII-3)
  - Puck's seminar, talk to, 10 Dec. 1974 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Purdue, talks, Jan. 1967 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Questions on measure in non-compact spaces, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Series VII-3)
  - Random processes and operators, talk (Box Series VII-4)
  - Regis College, talk, 1974 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Remarks made to G. C. Rota on the four color problem..., 1972 (Box Series VII-4)
  - "Reminiscences and projections," talk at Princeton JVN meeting, 1972 (Box Series VII-4)
    ms. of talk
  - Rockefeller, talk, 15 Nov. 1983 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Rockefeller Institute, lecture and discussion, 27 Feb. 1964 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Role of mathematical abstractions in physical theories, 1979 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Rome, talk, 9 May 1963 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Roof article conference on nature, human nature, mathematics, and logic and political order, 1965 (Box Series VII-4)
    Summary minutes
  - Rota, conversation with Gian-Carlo (Box Series VII-4)
    - Part I, 1971-82 (Box Series VII-4)
      Transcripts of audio tapes (includes table of contents)
    - Part II, 1971-82 (Box Series VII-4)
      Transcripts of audio tapes
  - St. John's, talk at, 26 Oct. 1956 (Box Series VII-4)
  - St. John's, talk, 1981 (Box Series VII-4)
  - St. John's College, lecture, 24 Oct. 1975 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Salt Lake [City], talk, 1982 (Box Series VII-4)
  - San Antonio, talk, 1970 (Box Series VII-4)
  - [Sane?] meeting, talk in. Los Alamos, 8 July 1959 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Sanibel [Island, FL] symposium, talk, 1975 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Santa Barbara, talk, 3 Sept. 1968 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Schnectedy, talk, 1979 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Scottish Book, talk on. Austin, TX, 1982 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Scottish Book conference, 4-5 May 1979 (Box Series VII-4)
    Schedule and participants
  - Scottish Book conference, 1979 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Scottish Book conference, talk, 1973;n.d. (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar, 21 Sept. 1971; 2 folders (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar, 6 Feb. 1975 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar, 6 Mar. 1975 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar, 10 Apr. 1975 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar, 17 Apr. 1975 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar, 5 Feb. 1980 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Seminar talk, 24 Jan. 1980 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Set-theory and comb[?], lecture on. Rockefeller Institute, 24 Feb. 1969 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Siam, talk, 12 June 1967 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Siam meeting, talk, 27 Nov. 1968 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Sierpinski lecture. Banach Inst., 1978 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Slowly changing aspects of mathematics, the. Univ. of New Mexico, Taos conference, 1977 (Box Series VII-4)
  - [Socorro?], talk, 26 Feb. 1966 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Some problems of combinatorics and some mathematical ideas in biology, 23 Mar. 1976 (Box Series VII-4)
    Announcement
  - Speculations on some possible mathematical frameworks for the foundations of certain physical problems, 1984 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Study of some combinational problems on computers. Talk at Case Inst. Of Technology, 12 Apr. 1963 (Box Series VII-4)
    Outline and announcement
  - Syracuse, talk, 28 Apr. 1964 (Box Series VII-4)
  - T-division seminar [Los Alamos], talk, 23 Mar. 1956 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Technical lecture, Berkeley, 3 Nov. 1957 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Technological genesis in Science. Sakharov meeting, talk at. NY, 1981 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Tel Aviv, talk, 24 Apr. 1960 (Box Series VII-4)
  - [Texas symposium on relativistic astrophysics, talk], 27 Jan. 1967 (Box Series VII-4)
    Outline and program
  - Transmutation theory, problems on, 28 June 1983 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Transformations and transmutations, Austin, Tex., 1982 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Travel, talk on. Los Alamos, 12 Sept. 1966 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Tuscon, talk, 17 Mar. 1961 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Unexpected in science, the, 1974 (Box Series VII-4)
  - University, talk to the, 1971 (Box Series VII-4)
  - University of Colorado, talk, 23 Aug. 1957 (Box Series VII-4)
  - University of Illinois, talk, 2 May 1956 (Box Series VII-4)
  - University of New Mexico, talk, 23 Mar. 1984 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Urbana, [Ill.], talk, 1949[?] (Box Series VII-4)
  - Vancouver, talk, 3 Mar. 1969 (Box Series VII-4)
  - von Neumann and computers. Los Alamos, 1979 (Box Series VII-4)
    Outline (on same pg.: Library Assoc. talk, 1976, outline)
  - von Neumann lecture, Boulder, 27 Aug. 1963 (Box Series VII-4)
  - von Neumann lecture, Boulder, 27 Aug. 1963 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Washington, talk, 1981 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Westinghouse, talk, 8 May 1956 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Westinghouse, talk, 27 Sept. 1966 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Yale, talk, 24 Apr. 1968 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Yale, talk, 23 Mar. 1970 (Box Series VII-4)
- Series VIII. Unpublished works, 1932-1984, 1.5 Linear feet 3 boxes
  Notes, graphs, data charts, outlines, abstracts, and autograph and typescript texts generated by Ulam during his many years of mathematical research. Writings are arranged alphabetically by title. This series represents the bulk of Ulam's research which was not published in its present form, but retained as a record of his works in progress. The earliest material of the series is Ulam's 1932 master's thesis for the Lwów Polytechnic Institute in Poland. The original manuscript of this work in Polish, entitled "O operacje produkto," was translated into English in 1973 as "On the operation of product." Both versions of the thesis are filed here.
  Box 2 consists entirely of notes, miscellaneous research material, and drafts for Ulam's second volume to the 1960 edition of A Collection of Mathematical Problems. Because Ulam passed away while this companion piece was in progress, the drafts were never published in the form intended. An index card file from Series VIII holding "problems for Problem Book II" is stored at the end of the collection.
  - Approximately convex functions, 1950 (Box Series VIII-1)
    Hyers, H. D.
  - Arithmetic complexity of integers, 1971 (Box Series VIII-1)
    Beyer, W. A.
    Stein, M. L.